Alexis Darío Estévez Salazar

Machine Learning Engineer

Quito, Ecuador (GMT-5) (+593) 9 78619435 adestevez93@outlook.es https://inkedin.com/in/adestevez/ https://adestevez.github.io/alexisestevez/

Machine Learning Engineer with more than 4 years of experience. Working in on premise and cloud environments from providers such as GCP, AWS, programming languages such as Python, JS, C++ and R converging on MLOps framework prioritizing CICD. My professional life has been involved in various industries such as Government, FinTech, EdTech among others. In which I have contributed to the creation and scaling of the company. The job changes have allowed me to consolidate my way of working to an agile framework and devotion to the quality of deliverables. Today I seek to help companies scale through the value of data, providing solutions that break down barriers and enable business change.

EXPERIENCE

KUSHKI, Data & Reporting Analyst — June, 2021 - Feb-2023

- Responsible for the integration of data from various project management sources through process automation, reducing by 90% the number of missing parts and inconsistencies.
- Design and deployment of more than 10 high impact reports for company founders for product validation in the market, as well as project delivery, which allowed decision making in the market.
- Product metrics gathering through conversation with stakeholders and validation of the same through analytical processes, improving workflow and reducing turnaround time.

Tech Stack: Redshift, Elastic Search, Kibana, GCP AppScript, GCP Bigquery, GCP Cloud Functions, GCP Cloud Storage, Data Studio, Slack, Asana, Jira, SCRUM, Python, R, JavaScript

1 Mentor, Machine Learning Engineer — May, 2021 - Present

- Development of Machine Learning applications, oriented to the mission and vision of the company. These are framed in the field of EdTech, seeking to improve the employability of students in Canada and the United States.
- Helped design the deployment workflow of the area, using external tools and services oriented to agile project management under the Scrum framework.
- Using cloud services such as GCP (Vertex AI), models are developed and made available for pre-production and production. Using the MLOps framework I have done integrations with Artifact, looking for an adequate CI/CD, maintaining security standards and high availability.
- Currently I am leading the transition of processes oriented to the product strategy with perspective to the launch of MVPs, in which I consider data as an economic asset.

Tech Stack: GCP Vertex AI, GCP Cloud Functions, GCP Bigquery, GCP Compute Engine, Postgresql, GCP Dataproc, Spark, Docker, MLOps, Scikit Learn, PyTorch, Data Flow, Slack, ClickUP, Flask, Django, Python, R, JavaScript, FastAPI, Kubeflow

Asamblea Nacional del Ecuador, Lead of Analytics — February, 2020 - June 2021

• Responsible for the analysis of legislative processes. Economic auditing using stochastic processes and econometrics towards different functions of the Ecuadorian state. (Confidential Information)

Tech Stack: GCP Vertex AI, GCP Cloud Functions, GCP Bigguery, GCP Compute Engine, Python, R, C++, Looker

PUCE, Infrastructure Engineer — January, 2019 - January 2020

- Management of data center and infrastructure corresponding to LTIC (Faculty of Engineering).
- Management and direction of software (Machine Learning) projects under agile methodologies.
- Analysis and reporting of project status to the different areas through prospective data analysis.

Tech Stack: HPE Servers, UNIX, NGINX, VMWare, Laravel, NodelS, Django, Flask Python, R, Javascript

PROJECTS

CEYA TECH

- Development of multiplatform applications applied to NFC technology.
- Development of web applications for the management of export companies.
- Maintenance and support of on premise infrastructure.

Alexis Darío Estévez Salazar

Machine Learning Engineer

(+593) 9 78619435 <u>adestevez93@outlook.es</u> <u>https:/linkedin.com/in/adestevez/</u> <u>https://adestevez.github.io/alexisestevez/</u>

Quito, Ecuador (GMT-5)

SKILLS

Programming Languages: Advanced: Python, R, C++, JavaScript; Intermediate: TypeScript, Scala, Java; Basic: Dart, Go,

Frameworks Tools: Advanced: Django, Flask, FastAPI, Laravel, AWS, GCP, DOCKER; Intermediate: NodeJS;

Data Base: Advanced: MongoDB, Redshift, Bigguery, Postgresql; Intermediate: SQL Server.

Tools

Agile: SCRUM, Kanban

Languages: Fluent: English; Native: Spanish.

EDUCATION

Universidad Internacional de la Rioja – Rioja, Spain. *Master of Science, Big Data & Visual Analytics, Mar 2020*Universidad de las Fuerzas Armadas "ESPE" – Rumiñahui, Ecuador. *Bachelor of Science, Electronics & Telecommunications*Engineering, Nov 2018

CERTIFICATIONS

Modernizing Data Lakes and Data Warehouses with Google Cloud, Google Cloud

Bioinformática en R, PUCE

Como escalar Scrum con Scrum at Scale, Udemy

Design Principles for Effective Dashboard Design, Udemy

Elastic Stack 7. Beats, Logstash, Elasticsearch, Kibana ELK, Udemy

Design Thinking | De Cero a MAESTRO [2022], Udemy

Gestión de Proyectos, Udemy

Docker Essentials, Udemy

Scrum Foundation Professional Certificate SFPC, Certiprof

Scrum Master Professional Certificate SMPC, Certiprof

DevOps Essentials Professional Certificate DEPC, Certiprof

AWS Cloud Practitioner Essentials, AWS

Oracle Cloud Infrastructure Foundations 2021 Associate, Oracle

Cloud & Virtualization, VMWare

Network Virtualization, VMWare

Software Defined Storage, VMWare

NDG Linux Unhatched, Academia Linux

NDG Linux Essentials, Academia Linux

Introducción a la Seguridad Cibernética, CISCO

Servidor Linux: Instalación y administración, Linked In Learning

Laravel 5 Essential Training: 1 The basics, Linked In Learning

Business Leader Path, Databricks Academy

Python for Data Science, IBM Cognitive Class

Data Analysis Using Python, IBM Cognitive Class

Data Visualization Using Python, IBM Cognitive Class

Machine Learning with Python, IBM Cognitive Class

Big Data 101, IBM Cognitive Class

Professional Python , DataCamp

Machine Learning with MATLAB, Mathworks Training Services

Data Processing and Visualization with MATLAB, Mathworks Training Services

M001: MongoDB Basics, MongoDB University

M103: Basic Cluster Administration, MongoDB University

M201: MongoDB Performance, MongoDB University

NSE Certified 1 Network Security Associate, Fortinet NSE Institute

NSE Certified 2 Network Security Associate, Fortinet NSE Institute

Transformación digital para el empleo, Google Activate

Cloud Computing, Google Activate

Gestión de proyectos ágiles e innovación con SCRUM y Design Thinking, NEXTECH ITIL 4 Foundation, NEXTECH

Big Data: el impacto de los datos masivos en la sociedad actual, Universitat Autònoma de Barcelona Big Data: procesamiento y análisis, Universitat Autònoma de Barcelona

Big Data: adquisición y almacenamiento de datos, Universitat Autònoma de Barcelona Google Cloud Big Data and Machine Learning Fundamentals, Google Cloud

Machine Learning for Business Professionals, Google Cloud